[narrator] Long, long ago,
a great calamity emerged
from the depths of the Ashen Sea.
Its form was that of a great beast
that destroyed all in its path,
and Nergal was its name.
Through the ages, many warriors
challenged the malevolent force
known as the King of Ash,
but all were defeated.
People had given up
on fighting the threat so long ago,
the idea of resisting
seemed a distant memory.
But then a new warrior
was about to be born.
[electrical buzzing]
[theatrical music playing]
[gasps]
[Zirco sobbing] Sapphire! Oh, Sapphire!
Oh, please, please!
Sapphire, please. Sapphire!
[Sapphire groans]
[Zirco] Are you all right?
Sapphire, wait.
Your arm.
-[Sapphire] I'm fine…
-Ooh, ooh.
…Zirco.
[both gasp]
[Sapphire] What happened?
It's all destroyed. There's nothing left.
[Sapphire groaning softly]
[mumbled voice in a distance]
Ah. Mother, is that you?
-[mumbled voice in a distance continues]
-[Sapphire whimpers]
[Sapphire] Mother! I'll get you out!
[Zirco] Don't hurt yourself more.
It must be blocked by the rubble.
Mother, I'm coming!
I'm gonna get you out of there! Hold on!
[Queen] Sapphire, it's no use.
What?
No, Mother! What do you mean?
I can defeat the Nergal!
I'm more powerful than that thing!
I'll put an end to that atrocity
once and for all!
Damn it! I'll open the door!
Open up! I'll save you all!
I'll save you and Father
and everyone in the kingdom!
I'm going to protect everyone,
every last person! So, open up!
[sobbing] Come on! Mother!
Open the door, Mother! Help me! Open it!
Trying to fight against this world
is meaningless.
Why can't you understand that?
You're going to have to face the truth,
Sapphire. We've been defeated.
[Sapphire] But, Mother, why would…
No, not yet. I'll stay and fight.
I'll destroy that Nergal,
whatever it takes!
[Queen] Sapphire,
there's nothing you can do to stop it.
It's over. Accept it.
The only way that we can survive
is to flee from those stronger than them.
This whole world can perish and rot,
-but my final wish… [muffled speaking]
-[rumbling]
No, I…
[sobbing] Mother, no! Please!
-Open the door! You can't!
-I'm sorry,
-Mother, you can't!
-but I've gotta get out of here.
-[Sapphire] Stop it! Let go!
-[Zirco straining]
[Sapphire] Let go of me!
[rumbling]
[passengers whimpering,
indistinct talking]
[groans softly]
[Sapphire] The Nergal.
[cawing]
[rumbling in distance]
[Sapphire groaning]
Oh?
[Zirco] Sapphire!
[Zirco chuckling]
Ah! I'm soaked to the bone.
All righty then.
[groans softly]
What are you doing over there, Zirco?
[Zirco] I'm making you
a little something special.
Special?
Something that ought to help
liven up your spirits.
You know I'm not in the mood
to do anything.
Besides, Mother always told me
to avoid doing anything unnecessary.
[Zirco] Well, I'll have to offer
the Queen my contrition,
because this is your new weapon, Sapphire.
A weapon suited
to help us survive out here.
It will allow you to hold things,
to carry things, and even to hug people.
If we hope to make it in this world,
we're going to have to start working
and earning our keep.
That's not the same.
[low growl]
[gasps] Oh, no.
[groaning]
[straining]
Trying to fight against this world
is meaningless.
Why can't you understand that?
[screams]
[Zirco] What's all the ruckus?
[screams] Sapphire! Look out!
[Sapphire groans]
[effort scream]
[grunts]
Huh?
-Oh, Sapphire!
-[gasps]
Oh, thank goodness you're all right.
-[Sapphire] Zirco.
-[sobbing]
[enchanting music playing]
[electrical buzzing]
[choir music playing]
Now let us pray.
May the Angel of Hope guide us.
[congregation] May the Angel of Hope
guide us.
[indistinct chatter]
[woman] Here you go. Thank you.
[girl] No, thank you.
And I hope you enjoy it.
[man] One loaf, please.
Here you go.
I, uh, don't suppose you could make
the loaf a little cheaper today.
-Uh--
-It's just, work's been drying up,
and I'm barely making it as is.
Uh, well, I…
[chuckles]
[sighs]
[moaning weakly]
[screams]
[eerily] Can you spare some food, please?
[groans]
Jeez, come on.
What am I supposed to do?
Um, you all right?
[Sapphire sniffing] Smells so good.
Ah! That smell! That smells amazing!
Uh, well, uh… See, I'm selling them
for 50 gold each. Interested?
I should have known. I don't have any.
I had a feeling.
Oh. Well, I can't just let you starve!
[Zirco and Sapphire chomping]
-[father] Oh.
-[chomping continues]
You two must not have eaten for some time.
While they are welcome here,
maybe next time
you can just bring them the leftovers.
Sorry, Mom. I wasn't sure
I could make that kind of decision.
I haven't been able to enjoy
a hot meal for so long.
I really appreciate it.
[girl] Uh, of course.
[father] Sounds like food's
been hard to come by.
We were forced from our homeland
seven years ago.
Since then, we couldn't find work,
so we've been wandering
from place to place,
eating whatever food we can find.
[mother] All too familiar a story.
-Awful, nonetheless.
-[father] Mmm.
An old woman and a young girl
all on their own.
I imagine it's been rough.
It's so good!
This thing is delicious! What is it?
[chuckles] That is a bone
in Golden Rat steak.
[father] It's one of their
local specialties here in Gold Land.
[Sapphire chomping loudly]
So this is the Golden Rat steak.
Mmm. I've got room for more!
-Can I have another helping? [laughing]
-[mother] I wish I could,
but if you want more, you'll have to pay.
-Times are hard for us, too.
-[Sapphire] Oh, right.
Of course.
We're willing to do anything.
Please, can we work for you?
[father] We've got all the help we need.
Do you know anywhere around here
that's looking for workers?
In my experience, when outsiders
are looking to make money quickly,
it's the mines that they turn to first.
It's not the kind of work I'd recommend.
[Sapphire sighs]
I can't just sit around
feeling sorry for myself forever.
I'll do it.
Can you take me there?
What? Now?
Uh, um…
Don't tell me you're planning to go,
looking like that.
[Sapphire and Zirco exclaim]
[father] Fine. Draw them a bath, will you?
[both laughing]
[Sapphire] I'm Sapphire. Nice to meet you.
-[Pine] My name's Pine.
-[Sapphire] Pine? That's such a cute name.
[Pine] Do… Do you really think so?
[Sapphire] Originally,
I'm from Silver Land, but…
It's a long story,
and kind of a sad one, too,
-but anyway…
-[Pine] I bet it was hard.
But now I'm glad to see
that you're doing better.
Welcome to Gold Land!
[Sapphire chuckles] Thanks.
[bell tolling]
[Velvet] The devastation of Silver Land
suffered like no other,
but we've been able to enjoy
relative peace since the calamity.
However, the King of Ash is stirred
and the Nergal are active again.
And as a result, it has slowed
the pace of our mining operation.
[man 1] What more can you tell us
about the source of crystal energy
discovered the other day?
[Velvet] It has been sealed off
and is being investigated.
[man 1] Be cautious
that it doesn't provoke the King of Ash.
[Velvet] Understood.
[man 2] Our nation's finances
continue to be strained,
what with crystal prices
soaring higher than ever.
[man 1] And the black market
is only gaining momentum.
[Velvet] The miners and immigrants
are becoming agitated.
Yesterday they began chanting,
"Defeat the King of Ash" again,
which led to another riot.
Then suppress them by any means.
It is said the Angel of Hope
is the only one who can defeat
the King of Ash, is it not?
That's a dangerous idea.
Any individual caught
disseminating harmful notions,
or rumors, will be apprehended at once,
and will be subject
to public whipping for their crime.
Understood.
[Pope] We must not resist the King of Ash.
If we want to survive,
we have no choice but to bear the pain.
May the Angel of Hope guide us.
[all] May the Angel of Hope guide us.
[Sapphire and Zirco] Mmm.
Off we go!
You helped me get registered
and everything. Thanks so much.
You'll be starting tomorrow. You ready?
Yeah.
I've got some business
I have to take care of.
Why don't you two go on ahead without me?
Huh? What business?
[Zirco snickers]
You'll just have to wait and see.
Wait, Zirco, that's not fair.
[Pine chuckles]
Oh, it's nothing.
But there's lots more
interesting stuff over there.
Huh? Really?
-Shall we go?
-Mmm. Yeah.
[laughing]
[inhales, sighs]
[Pine] Mom, you'd be so proud of me!
I think I might have just made
my first friend.
Huh? What's wrong?
Huh? Really, it's nothing.
Come on. You can tell me.
Look! They're cooking up one of the famous
Golden Rat dishes over there!
Huh?! Whoa!
[screaming] Did you say "Golden Rat?"
Oh, that was close.
I'm here all proud of myself
for making a friend,
and I don't even know
what Sapphire thinks of me.
[Sapphire screams] Where is it?
Where is it?
-Huh?
-[Sapphire] What's that?
Oh, no, not there.
[both panting]
Why did you do that?
[Pine] The stores on the north side
are for upperclass customers only.
[Sapphire] Upperclass customers?
-How many times do I have to tell you…
-[Sapphire] Oh, I understand.
That means outsiders
aren't allowed either.
[Pine] What is it?
[Sapphire] My country
had stuff like this, too.
Not that any of that matters now.
The Nergal didn't care about status,
and just destroyed everything.
[Pine] Oh, I'm sorry.
[Sapphire] Oh, it's fine, really.
Nowadays, it doesn't matter to me
whether someone's upperclass or common.
I just want to try to find
a way to help people.
I keep trying to figure out
what I have to offer, though.
Still haven't found it yet.
[Pine] Really? I feel the exact same.
-[Sapphire] Huh?
-There's something inside of me
that's always pushing me to help others,
but then I get nervous and I freeze up.
I mean, I'm not really good at anything.
What's someone like me even suited for?
Pine, you're just like me, then.
I'm not like you at all.
Your home country fell apart,
but that didn't stop you
from surviving on your own.
You're amazing. I could never do that.
I can barely do anything.
I'm hardly amazing.
I mean, I still haven't helped anybody.
I have an idea.
Let's try and find something
we can do together.
But if that's the case,
then you're gonna have to be my friend.
[gasps] Friends?
[Sapphire] F-R-I-E-N-D-S.
Friends. [chuckles]
[Zirco] Sapphire! I found a place
where we can stay!
[Sapphire] Wow, really?
Thank you so much, Zirco.
-Hey, Zirco?
-[Zirco] What is it, Sapphire?
I made a friend who's my age
for the first time.
Mmm. Did you, now?
[breathing deeply]
[Zirco] Asleep already, are you?
I'm happy for you, Sapphire.
[bell tolling]
[groans softly]
[both gargle]
[bell continues tolling]
[Rock] All right, guys.
Sapphire and Zirco here
will be joining our group.
-Nice to meet you.
My name is Rock, and I'm the leader.
This is Chorogy,
-and next to him is Hecate.
-[scoffs]
-My name is Chick.
-And my name is Tack.
[Sapphire] You guys look exactly alike.
[Chorogy] Sheesh. So they finally decided
to send us reinforcements,
and what do we get? An old lady.
[Rock] Hey, come on, Chorogy.
[Zirco chuckles] Even old ladies
have to work
for their food somehow, you know.
-[punches]
-[groans]
-[workers clamoring]
-Right, now restrain him.
You were the one who was leading that riot
the other day, weren't you?
Ugh. Damn it all.
Why are we the ones always forced
to do the dangerous work?
Come on, everyone!
Raise the rallying cry! Fight!
Are you finished with your ranting now?
You have us scraping to the King of Ash,
when that Nergal's just going
to kill us all eventually!
But you Mitra just sit and watch!
You bastards think you can--
-[punch lands]
-[groaning]
Throw him in solitary. Take him away.
Let me remind you all of the rules here.
No one must ever defy the King of Ash!
Instead, be grateful to the King of Ash
that you remain alive.
Now get back to work!
May the Angel of Hope guide us.
[Rock] Velvet, that bastard.
[Sapphire] Who's he?
[Rock] One of the Mitra in charge
of managing the mining site.
[Sapphire] I can tell
I don't like him already.
[Rock] Trust me, it'd be best
if you don't do anything
to draw his attention.
So, how much of this crystal
should I be digging up?
As much as you can.
The more crystals you unearth,
the more you get paid.
More crystals means more money? [yelps]
There's a little Golden Rat steak
with my name on it.
Moron. You make it sound like it's easy.
What do you mean by "Moron"?
Come on, newbie.
There's no beginner's luck on this job.
I don't need luck. I've got skill.
All right, then,
if you dig up more than I do,
-you can have my whole share.
-[screams] Really?
[Sapphire] All right, crystals.
Come to mama!
Huh?
-[effort screaming]
-She's really giving it her all.
She'll wear herself out like that.
Come on. There's a better spot there.
-[Chick] What's with that machine?
-[Tack] She's cheating. Not fair.
[Zirco] I may not look it,
but this old lady is a genius inventor.
[Hecate and Chorogy] One, two. One, two.
One, two. One, two. One, two. One, two.
[Rock sighs]
Nice work today, guys.
We might even finish early.
[Sapphire] One, two.
One steak, two steaks.
One steak, two steaks. Two steaks for me!
[Chorogy] Is her yield increasing?
Focus on your own work.
Why do you turn everything
into a competition?
And how did I get involved?
Could you be more annoying?
[rat squealing]
[screaming]
What do you think you're doing?!
Sorry. I didn't do it on purpose.
That's a bad sign.
-[explosion]
-[gasps] Huh?
[grunts, pants]
[gasps] A Nergal?
But wait, it doesn't look like the one
that came to Silver Land.
[clamoring in distance]
The Nergal's back again.
Yes, sir. Lord Velvet,
you should evacuate, too.
Get as many of the remaining miners
as possible to safety.
I'm afraid we can't afford
to lose any more workers.
[both guards] Yes, sir.
-[people screaming]
-[man] Quickly! Keep moving!
-You, don't stop!
-[guard] Move!
-Get yourself to higher ground! Quickly!
-[guard] Keep moving!
-[woman 1] Are you all right?
-[man panting]
[woman 2] Hurry up!
[wailing]
[sighs] This is all my fault.
[Rock] Forget about that for now.
We gotta run.
Can't we do something
other than running away?
[man gasps]
[screaming]
-[Rock] Newbie!
-Oh, no!
[continues screaming]
[Zirco] Oh, no. Sapphire! Sapphire!
Sapphire! Where are you? Sapphire!
[groans]
Oh, I'm sorry I didn't see you there.
You better get going.
See ya.
[Tack groaning]
[whimpers]
Here. Hold on.
Thanks, lady.
[both gasp]
[both voices shaking] We… We're done for.
[Zirco yelps]
[all screaming]
-You gotta be kidding.
-What about Tack?
[lullaby music playing]
[Sapphire] After losing everything,
being disposed of,
left all alone, I couldn't do anything.
And now I just die here?
[Queen] Trying to fight
against this world is meaningless.
Why can't you understand that?
[Sapphire] No,
I can't let it end like this.
I haven't gotten anything back!
[banging]
[captivating music playing]
[music intensifies]
Huh? What's all this?
[groaning]
Hecate!
[whimpering]
[Sapphire] Look out!
[Sapphire screaming]
[groans] What?! Was that really me?!
-The new girl?
-Sapphire, there you are!
What's going on?
What is she doing?
Who is this girl?
[Sapphire] Hey, guys!
Get away while you can!
[exclaims] Whoa!
[panting] Over there!
I've got this.
Ha! [grunts, strains]
[Nergal roars]
[effort scream]
Yahoo! [laughs]
[laughs]
Huh? Cool!
[horse neighs]
Let's get you out of here.
[Nergal growling]
[man groans]
Oh, no. It's headed this way.
They're in trouble. [grunts]
What do I do now?
-[Rock] She's not affected by the mold?
-[Chick] Incredible.
She's like a knight or something.
Sapphire!
[both] You can do it!
[chuckles]
Everyone, I'm so sorry.
[woman] What's going on down there?
Something's strange.
[man] Is someone fighting it?
Huh?
What's happening?
Someone's actually fighting
one of the Nergal?
I doubt we'll be able to use
this mining site after this.
But we do have this guy's team
to thank for saving us. [chuckles]
[straining]
[screaming]
[gasps]
Well, that's no help.
What do I do?
Huh? What's this?
This should work.
[dramatic music playing]
[effort scream]
[cheering]
[scoffs]
The Princess Knight to the rescue.
[Nergal wailing]
Is the Nergal really running away?
I don't believe it.
Whoa! It's running away!
-It's retreating!
-[exclaims] Hooray!
[all cheering]
[guard] You're saying
that the Nergal ran away?
[Velvet] Which team was present? Tell me.
Yes, sir. The team I saw the closest to it
down there was Rock's crew.
Isn't that right, Chorogy?
Yes, it's exactly as he said.
Could this be the work
of a demon, or was it…
-Mmm?
-No.
-Bring Rock's crew to me at once!
-[guard 1] Yes, sir.
Count the miners and check for casualties,
-and tend to the injured!
-[guard 2] Yes, sir!
[Queen] This whole world
can perish and rot.
But my final wish is that you live on.
Good boy. Thanks for all your help.
[chuckles]
So, how do I… How does this thing work?
Come on!
There's gotta be a switch or something!
[gasps]
Oh. [gasps]
-Well, that did it.
-[people approaching]
At least it's over for now.
-[Tack] There!
-[Zirco] I see her!
-[Sapphire] Oh, you're safe.
-Sapphire!
-[Chick] Thank you.
-[Tack] Thank you so much.
Are you all right, sapphire?
-You're not hurt, are you?
-No, but I am a bit…
A bit tired.
-[all gasp]
-[Zirco] Sapphire!
[crying] I'm sorry. So sorry, Sapphire.
I'm the one who was a moron.
What are you crying about?
Sapphire, you're amazing. I mean it.
[sobbing] I'm gonna give you
all of my crystals!
[Sapphire] I don't need all that, Hecate.
But how about this?
[chuckles]
[all laughing]
[electrical buzzing]
[indistinct talking]
[Rock] Well, we didn't see
anyone like that.
Clearly, someone is responsible.
If you're caught lying to me,
the punishment is death.
Death?
Once the King of Ash has been provoked,
the Nergal will return
to destroy us completely.
Which means your jobs
are on the line as well.
That Nergal tripped on its own tail,
bit its tongue,
-and scurried off whimpering.
-[Velvet] Enough.
Uh, you know…
-[Velvet] What is it?
-Actually… [groans]
Your threats will get you nowhere.
Fine, then.
But should you notice anything,
I expect a report.
[Rock] Indeed, if we do,
we'll let you know.
Listen up. I won't have
any of us selling out our own.
We don't know anything about the person
who fought that Nergal, understand?
I appreciate it.
[guard 1] Sir, what do you think?
Were they telling the truth?
What happened here today
is strictly confidential.
It does not leave this room.
-[guard 1] But, sir--
-I'm serious.
And I will take
full responsibility for it.
[Rock] To our safe return!
[all] Cheers!
-[Pine's father] Take this.
-Sure.
[Hecate] Tonight, drinks are on me!
[all cheering]
[Pine] Sorry for the wait, Sapphire.
Here's your favorite.
[exclaims]
Come on, Pine, you too.
Let's have a toast.
Huh? All right. Cheers.
[both chuckle]
Mmm. [satisfied sigh]
I've been waiting for you, Golden Rat.
It's so good.
I wish I could stay,
but I have to help the other customers.
Sorry, I don't want to keep you.
I just wanted to make sure
I shared some of this joy with you, Pine.
Oh, don't apologize.
I've been so busy,
I'm the one who should say sorry.
When I heard a Nergal had appeared again,
I was so surprised.
[exclaims] You know?
In all honesty, I wasn't sure
I was gonna make it.
But everyone is talking about
how amazing you were.
[laughs]
It was luck. That's all.
-[Pine's father] Pine!
-Oh.
Uh, hey, Sapphire.
I've been thinking about
what I can do to help people, too.
Ta-da! I wanna share my ideas with you!
Really? I love that.
I better get back to work.
[Sapphire] You got this.
[sighs]
[Endo] It's wild, though,
because if it weren't for that knight,
there wouldn't be this many survivors.
[man] Quiet. Rock told us
not to talk about that.
[Endo] It's fine. We're celebrating today.
We're letting loose. So what if our lips
get loose, too? [laughs]
[Sembry] Oh, dear knight,
oh, Angel of Hope,
please eliminate all the Nergal for us!
-[Chorogy] What are you talking about?
-What's wrong with you?
[Chorogy] The Mitra are always saying
that if you anger the King of Ash,
terrible things will happen.
Now, wait a second. Last time I checked,
you're an immigrant too, Chorogy.
Now you're gonna side
with the Gold Landers?
We lied to them.
If they find out, they'll kill us.
[Sembry] Shut your mouth.
And why should I?
I haven't said anything wrong!
-[Sembry] You've got more to say?
-[Rock] That's enough, Chorogy.
Tonight, all the drinks are on me,
so no fighting.
Sorry about getting you dragged
into this, Chorogy.
-[Chorogy grunts]
-[Rock] Wait.
[sighs] What's his problem?
Whatever. Let's party!
[all] Yeah!
[Pine humming]
It's not fair.
You give Sapphire a little attention,
and suddenly she's all full of herself
just because she took out
one of the Nergal.
[man] Hey, you.
[Chorogy groaning]
[Chorogy screaming]
[Zirco] I must say, that thing
came as quite a surprise.
What thing?
That thing you're wearing
on your head, Sapphire.
Uh, my ribbon?
Mmm. I'd like to take
a closer look at that thing.
[straining]
Why isn't it doing it?
[Zirco] Are you trying
to keep me in suspense?
[straining]
Ooh!
I think maybe it has something
to do with the crystals.
Hmm. If I'm honest,
I don't really understand it myself.
And your body feels perfectly fine, right?
Mmm, yeah. I feel great.
Maybe even better than ever.
[sighs in relief] I'm glad to hear it.
[sobs softly]
It must have been scary.
I'm so proud of you, Sapphire.
There's nothing you can do to stop it.
It's over, accept it.
Hey, Zirco, I found it.
I know what I want to do.
I know what my purpose is.
-[Zirco] Helping people?
-Mmm.
But it's more than just fighting Nergal
as the Princess Knight.
Anyone who's been struggling
deserves my help.
And I think I survived
to be that kind of hero.
And I'm your support.
If there's anything
you need this genius inventor to make,
you let me know.
Mmm. Thanks, Zirco.
Hmm? Actually…
[pleasant music playing]
[man 1] Oh, dear.
The fire is spreading faster
than they can put it out. What's that?
Is that the cry of someone
who's been left behind?
What will they do now?
[man 2] Princess Knight to the rescue!
Alley-oop!
[man 1] And just like that,
the young girl was rescued.
[man 1] I saw that in real life.
[woman] She was incredible, wasn't she?
[man 2] The Princess Knight
appeared again, huh?
[man 1] You know,
she saved my life once, too.
[chuckles]
[Pine] Ta-da!
I'm still not sure
what exactly I can do to help people,
but I started by writing down
the things that I'm good at.
Oh. Like what?
The first one I wrote down is singing.
-Wow, Pine, I love it!
-Welp, I actually said it out loud.
Then this will be perfect.
Uh? [screams]
[Sapphire] Ta-da!
[gasps loudly] What have you got?
[flute playing]
-It's a flute.
-[exclaims]
I was right.
Something told me you loved music.
Why wouldn't you?
Music has the ability
to lift people's spirits.
[chuckles] Yeah. Exactly.
-Why don't we give it a try right now?
-Sure.
[Pine] ♪ Long, long ago ♪
♪ There was a lone girl ♪
♪ Who wandered the land ♪
♪ Winter-worn and hungry ♪
-[footsteps approaching]
-Uh.
Huh.
You're that miner, Sapphire, aren't you?
Yeah, that's right.
[foreboding music playing]
[grunts]
What do you want?
Why have you brought me here?
[intense music playing]
[both grunting]
[yelps]
[gasping]
[Velvet] So you're this Ribbon Demon?
That power of yours, where did you get it?
A power that can even defeat a Nergal.
Did you undergo some kind
of special training?
How is it that you're unaffected
by the mold?
-[Sapphire] I don't know.
-Answer me. Don't pretend to be stupid.
But I'm telling the truth.
I accidentally fell into a glowing pool
at the mining site,
and the power
just started flowing out of me.
Are you saying it was the crystals?
The body cannot survive that potent
an influx of concentrated photon energy.
You're an immigrant.
What country are you from?
I come from Silver Land.
[scoffs] Silver Land, huh?
It's all destroyed now.
I know who you are.
You are the… The cursed princess.
[gasps]
You bear the responsibility
for the destruction of Silver Land.
You escaped your destiny.
Even if it meant the destruction
of your kingdom,
the queen wouldn't let you die.
How profoundly deep a mother's love is.
[Sapphire] Wait a moment.
I don't understand anything you're saying.
[Velvet] You really don't know?
Nergals feed on pure souls.
Had the proper sacrifices been made,
your kingdom could have avoided ruin.
In the country of Silver Land,
it is the pure soul of the princess
that has given as an offering.
-You mean me?
-Precisely.
But your mother, the Queen,
would not allow it.
And as a result, your home was destroyed.
You could even say you destroyed it,
Princess Sapphire.
That can't be.
I would never.
You bear a curse, and now you want
to unleash it in our land?
To bring Gold Land to ruin?
Provoking the King of Ash
will bring nothing else.
But the power of this ribbon,
it can defeat the Nergal.
I'm trying to tell you that power
will prove nothing but a calamity.
No one asked you to intervene.
[breath trembling] All the same,
this power must be useful somehow.
So why don't you help me?
How am I supposed to break my curse?
How was it done if not by fighting?
[yawns]
-[panting, exclaims]
-Ow!
[groans] Come on, Chorogy.
Can't you watch where you're going, bozo?
-[groans]
-I'm sorry. I gotta--
You're not going anywhere.
Where have you been?
You've been slacking off work all week!
Something smells fishy.
[Pine] Why didn't I say anything?
Why didn't I try to stop them?
I'm the worst friend ever.
[Zirco sighs] Quite the haul today.
-Zirco.
-Oh. Is something the matter, Pine?
I think she's in trouble!
The Mitra came
and they took Sapphire away by force.
-The Mitra?!
-[Hecate] If you want to know the details,
-you can ask him.
-[groans]
Because he's the one who sold out
Sapphire's secret to Velvet
and the Mitra.
[Pine] Sapphire's secret?
What do you mean?
The one who defeated the Nergal,
the Princess Knight is…
Well, her real identity is Sapphire.
Quiet! Zirco!
But how did the two of you know about it?
I only know because she saved my life,
which is exactly what she did
for this slimy idiot.
And yet he still ratted her out!
It's not as simple as that.
The Mitra got me all by myself,
and they were grilling me.
I'm weak. I was scared.
But I never thought
they'd try to execute her.
But why?
[both] What do you mean, execute her?
I thought she'd be treated
just like all the other offenders.
That she'd be thrown in a jail cell.
[both] Huh?
But then Lord Velvet drew his sword
and went for her.
[sobbing] I'm so sorry. Please forgive me.
Oh, come on, Chorogy.
Why are you the one crying now?
I'll give you something to cry about.
Hang on, Sapphire! I'll be there soon!
Zirco's coming to save you now!
[Hecate] Are you really sorry?
[Chorogy sobbing]
-[Sapphire] Pine.
-[gasps]
[Pine] Sapphire?
-[chuckles] Sorry for making you worry.
-Sapphire!
Oh, thank goodness.
[Zirco] Huh? Sa… Sapphire!
You're all right!
-[Zirco sobbing]
-Huh?
[gasps loudly] She's alive!
I didn't mean to make you all worry.
-[Pine] How did you get away?
-[Chorogy] Thank heavens.
[Zirco] Don't tell me
you struck Velvet down!
Of course not.
I'm not sure how to say it.
It's a bit of a long story.
[electrical buzzing]
Let go of me right now!
I said, let me go!
-Now you let go! [grunting]
-[Velvet] Why did you bring her along?
Now that she knows,
she cannot leave here alive.
No matter how many times
we turned her away,
she kept following.
Shall I dispose of her?
-No, wait!
-If you do anything to my Sapphire,
I'll make sure you pay for it!
She can be trusted. She's not a spy.
[Velvet] Why should I believe that?
What, do you get some kind of sick kick
out of bullying an old woman?
[Velvet] Informants come in all shapes,
sizes and ages.
We've been together a long time.
She's family to me.
[Zirco] I'll make you all pay!
I mean it! [grunts]
-[Sapphire] I'm begging you.
-Let me go!
[grunting]
[scoffs] Very well, then.
-[Zirco] Let go of me!
-She makes one suspicious move,
she gets the sword.
Now hurry up.
Where we are headed today
is the Pillar of Creation.
They are gateways to the world
where the Nergal dwell.
In truth, the Nergal
are not creatures of this world.
They cannot be killed either.
They may not even be alive at all.
[Sapphire] These Nergal, what are they?
[Velvet] All I know for sure is that
they are beings that devour souls.
They can usually satiate
their hunger with crystals.
But if the crystals run low,
they come to the city
to devour human souls instead.
[Sapphire] Can a creature like that
even be defeated?
[Velvet] The Nergal are connected
to our world by components called factors,
and they could be destroyed.
Just one is not enough.
But destroy all of them,
and the King of Ash
could be severed from our world.
[Sapphire] How can you say that
with such certainty?
[Velvet] Look, at one time,
a great kingdom stood there.
No one alive remembers it now.
But I discovered
some of their ancient records,
and in them were accounts
of those who fought the Nergal.
[Sapphire] Even so, their kingdom
was still destroyed.
[Velvet] The Nergal that ravaged
this once great kingdom
was most likely the same
that attacked your homeland.
[Sapphire] What?
[Velvet] It has appeared
at regular intervals throughout history,
and caused the downfall of many a nation.
The Prime Nergal.
[Sapphire] So then,
I'll have to face that one, too?
[Velvet] The Prime Nergal's return
is the cataclysm the Mitra feared most.
Your powers might be
just what we need to understand
the truth behind the King of Ash.
And I intend to find out.
There it is.
[Sapphire] That's a Pillar of Creation?
[Velvet] The curse here is too strong.
We can get no closer,
or risk being infected.
What's the matter?
Have you lost your nerve
now that you've seen it?
Of course not. I'm ready.
[Zirco] Ah!
You're gonna want this.
Wow. You finished it already?
Press here, and voila.
That should come in handy.
Thank you so much, Zirco.
Hmm. Just promise
you'll come back in one piece.
[dramatic music playing]
The gateway.
Huh?
Ah!
[screaming]
[grunts]
The Princess Knight to the rescue.
What is this place? Where am I?
[gasps]
[gasps] It can't be.
Is that Mother and Father?
[groans]
[groaning]
The Nergal. They know I'm here.
[roars]
I haven't seen this.
[Sapphire screaming]
This thing is amazing.
Just four left.
Let's go.
[grunting]
That worked.
[effort scream]
[Queen] Sapphire.
You must not resist.
Don't fight,
even if the whole world should perish.
[majestic music playing]
[rumbling]
What's going on?
[whooshes]
All I have to do is destroy that?
All right.
[grunting, straining]
Did it work?
[whooshing]
[creaking]
-[whooshing]
-[Sapphire exclaims loudly]
[grunting]
Huh? What's all this now?
[tinkling melodically]
[yelling fearfully]
I'm in trouble! I'm in trouble!
[grunting]
[panting] It's falling!
[screaming]
[continues screaming]
[crackling]
Sapphire is still inside!
[exhales heavily]
[rumbling]
[wind howling]
[footsteps approaching]
[snickers softly]
[electrical buzzing]
-[jingles]
-[Sapphire] What's this?
-[coins jingle]
-[Sapphire, Zirco gasp]
It's your payment.
You never said the job came with payment!
Hmm. Why would you think it wouldn't?
Oh. [laughs exultantly]
[upbeat music playing]
[Zirco] Hmm.
[Zirco laughs gleefully]
Ah! There's no restaurant in town
that'll turn us away now!
-[Zirco giggling]
-[Sapphire chuckles]
[male server]
Roasted golden rat with herb sauce.
-[Sapphire and Zirco exclaim]
-Please enjoy.
[Sapphire and Zirco laughing]
[Sapphire and Zirco]
And without further ado…
[both gobble greedily]
[Pine] ♪ In a foreign tongue ♪
♪ From a distant land ♪
♪ You offered the same prayer
Again and again ♪
-I'm sorry.
-Huh?
I'm sure you had better things to do
than this on your day off.
What are you talking about, Pine?
This is just the kind of break I needed.
After all, Velvet's been working me
to the bone lately.
I think I've finally found it,
the reason that I survived.
Enough about me.
I want to hear more about
what you can do, Pine.
Sapphire! Don't push yourself too hard.
-[Hakobe] Wow!
-[gasps]
She's got a flute!
I told you to wait.
Stop, Hakobe.
Don't bother other people.
I'm not bothering anyone.
-[Nazuna] I guess you're just a kid.
-[gasps] Velvet?
[Nazuna] Why do you always have
to be like this, Hakobe?
You've got your bad habits too, Nazuna.
Why don't you join us?
Do you know this song?
Yeah.
it's "The Winter-Worn Traveler", right?
Would you play it again?
You must like music.
Yeah.
We're always singing
and learning new songs together.
Well, this is Pine,
and she's a really good singer, too.
-Shall we have a listen?
-Wait! Sapphire!
[both gasping]
-[flute playing]
-[Pine inhales]
♪ Long, long ago ♪
♪ A lone girl… ♪
-♪ Wandered the land… ♪
-[Sapphire] Huh?
[Pine struggles to sing]
[boys snickering]
[groans helplessly]
-[pops]
-Whoa!
Pine! Are you all right?
[Pine groaning]
[Pine groans softly]
[gasping]
[whimpers]
[sighs]
-Sorry for interrupting.
-[gasps]
Well…
No, not at all.
Don't worry about it.
Um, do you know those children?
[Velvet] They're my siblings.
This is where I was raised.
[kids] ♪ O King… ♪
Is something wrong?
It's just, Sapphire's been
coming home exhausted every day.
What are you making her do?
I'm giving her a chance to atone.
Atone for what?
She hasn't told you?
Maybe you should ask her yourself.
[kids] ♪ A blue bud ♪
[Pine] I know this song.
♪ A pure angel given in sacrifice ♪
I won't let them be sacrificed.
-[wind blowing]
-[grass rustling]
[squeaking]
[explosion booms]
[solemn music playing]
[men exclaiming]
[White Mitra] No, not here!
[Velvet]
The last confirmed sighting of a Nergal
was over three months ago.
The mining sites seem
to be recovering well.
In fact, our output
has not only rebounded,
but has significantly increased.
Excellent.
[Mitra] Moving on, we have more
information regarding the recent fire.
[White Mitra] Excuse the intrusion,
but there is something
that I must urgently bring
to Your Holiness' attention.
And you have no idea
as to what might have caused this?
[Velvet] I do not. None at all.
For now, our sterilization team
can keep things under control.
Should the situation get any worse,
we'll need to resort
to emergency provisions.
We should prepare the sacrificial rites,
should the need present itself.
[Velvet] Understood, Your Holiness
Velvet, after all we've done to raise you,
I trust I don't need to stress
that betrayal would be unforgivable.
You have nothing to fear.
I assure you, I will not disappoint you.
[footsteps approaching]
[door opens]
You called, so here I am.
[grunts softly]
What is it? What do you need?
Why make me sneak all the way in here?
[Velvet] We have to pause our mission.
We can't make any further attempts
to take down the Pillars or the Nergal.
[Sapphire] Huh? Why not?
The pillars of creation
have begun appearing at the city gate.
[Velvet] We must be cautious
not to provoke the King of Ash further.
[Sapphire] We have to do something.
We can't just let them grow.
[Velvet] The Mitra have their methods.
We'll just wait for things to settle down.
[Sapphire] Wouldn't it be faster
if I took care of it?
I'm not just gonna sit there and watch.
The Mitra are not so incompetent.
An infestation of this scale
can be handled.
The immigrant district
is right next to the gate.
If the growth gets out of hand…
more than one person
might become a victim.
[Velvet scoffs]
How do you expect to save the world
without sacrifice?
That's how you were saved…
by the sacrifice of your kingdom.
Hmm. That's why I want to change things.
If I know danger is approaching,
I can't ignore it.
I don't want to lose anyone else.
Do you think you're truly
capable of containing it?
If the Pillars of Creation
can't be stopped and keep growing,
and one of the Nergal appears once more,
the Mitra will have no choice
but to demand a sacrifice.
What are you talking about?
The sacrifices offered here
are the church's orphans.
[gasps]
They're like you, Sapphire,
doomed to a cursed fate.
I understand.
You want to save them.
Velvet, I can help.
How dare you presume to understand
someone else's heart?
Your little imagined reality
is not the same as my truth.
[exhales]
I'll do it.
I'll be the sacrifice.
After all, it was meant to be
my destiny in Silverland.
So if I can't stop it first,
I'll take their place.
Please.
Let me keep fighting till the end.
Don't let my power go to waste.
[electrical buzzing]
[White Mitra 1]
This area is currently sealed off.
-[man] You really have it under control?
-[White Mitra 2] Don't push.
Please, for your own safety.
We are asking all citizens
to remain inside their homes.
[White Mitra 3]
It seems to be contained for now.
[White Mitra 4] The pillar respawn rate
is also decreasing.
[White Mitra 5]
That very nearly took us to the brink,
but we're stopping it.
[people clamoring]
[clamor continues]
[Sapphire] Everyone, remain calm!
[dramatic music playing]
[people exclaiming]
The Princess Knight to the rescue!
-Oh!
It's the Princess Knight!
You don't need to worry.
[woman] Thank goodness!
[man] She'll save us!
[fire roaring]
[music continues]
[bleating]
[gasping]
[bubbling]
[explosion]
[people screaming]
[man] The tower is collapsing!
No way!
No, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no you don't!
That thing is huge.
Is she gonna be able to stop it?
[grunts]
[Pine panting]
[Zirco] Whoa!
What's going on?
[barking]
[Mitra 1] An evacuation order
has been issued.
All citizens must comply.
-Come, darling, this way.
-[Mitra 1] Women and children…
Can you tell us what's happening?
[sobbing]
[Mitra 2] It's going to be all right.
Do you know where your parents are?
[gate bangs loudly]
[guard 1] Move back! Move back!
[man] Wait! You can't do this.
[guard 2]
Full domestic lockdown is now in effect.
[people clamoring]
[bell clanging continuously]
-[Mitra] Found it.
-[White Mitra] Well done.
[bell continues clanging]
[Velvet] Pardon the intrusion,
Your Holiness.
-[cutlery clinks]
-[Pope] You may enter.
You summoned me, so I have dutifully come.
I suspect that you already know why.
[clanging]
[suspenseful music playing]
This is your doing, isn't it?
Yes.
[sighs wearily]
But Your Holiness,
I believe that girl may very well be
the Angel of Hope
that we have so long awaited.
With her mysterious powers, she was able
to successfully seal away a Nergal.
And not just once or twice.
I understand that toppling a Nergal
goes against the Mitra customs,
but the power she possesses
could potentially put an end
to all of our suffering, once and for all.
Velvet. Listen.
Yes, sir.
That immigrant girl,
she is not our Angel of Hope.
But Your Holiness--
You place far too much faith
in human beings.
[Velvet gasps]
We humans are not nearly as strong
as you hope and believe us to be.
It is an inescapable truth for all people,
including that girl.
And being the weak
and frail beings that they are,
when they are subjected
to cruel trials, they break.
That is why we, the Mitra,
must help guide and govern the hapless
and, at times, serve as a shield as well.
There must be another way.
Do not forget your teachings, Velvet.
Human beings are weak of heart and spirit.
Only by finding a common enemy
can they truly work together
for the progress of their kind.
This applies to you…
and yes, even to myself.
Your Holiness.
I can't just…
I have to do something.
The weak and frail creatures of this world
are sacrificed to power.
A law as constant as the sun.
Humankind is mercilessly
assailed by the King of Ash.
That is the unalterable
natural state of our existence.
Just as humans gain their sustenance
from Golden Rats,
humans, then, must serve
as nourishment for the king.
Humanity is happiest
when it is kept safe and cloistered,
where the illusion of peace eases them.
But you and the girl
have shattered that dream.
[Velvet breathes shakily]
[pensive music playing]
-[guard 1] Report the situation.
-[guard 2] Yes, sir.
It appears there is someone
fighting a Nergal at the city gate.
[guard 1 exhales] Let's move out!
[guard 2] Yes, sir.
[both panting]
[all gasping]
That can't be good.
Sapphire!
-[Chorogy] Time to take a stand!
-[all] Huh?
[snickers]
[Pine] Ch… Chorogy?
What the hell are you wearing?
Are you just gonna sit around
when we could be helping
the Princess Knight?
[Rock] Help her? How?
How are you gonna fight a Nergal?
What are you thinking?
[Chick and Tack] There's no way!
[Zirco] You could be killed!
I'm not sure how,
but even if we can't fight that thing,
there must be something we can do.
I've got things I want to protect, too.
If we want to help,
we gotta do it ourselves.
You're right, Chorogy.
You can count me in.
I'm always just the one getting saved.
It's about time I return the favor.
[gasps] I'll go, too!
[Chick] You're right. Let's do this.
[Tack] If Chorogy can find
the courage then…
[Zirco] I guess that leaves me no choice.
The old lady is in, too.
-[Chick and Tack] Yay!
-[Zirco] Let's do this.
[Rock] Sapphire needs us!
[clanging]
[crackling]
[panting]
It's no use.
They just keep coming.
[guard 1] What do you think you're doing?
[grunting]
Get your hands off!
[loud clanging]
[rumbling]
[all grunting]
Hmm?
Whoa!
[ominous music playing]
[Sapphire grunting, straining]
[effort scream]
[ominous music continues]
[lightning crashing]
[melancholy music playing]
[girl sobbing]
[woman sobbing]
[explosion]
[rumbling]
[whimpering]
What? What's going on?
[gasps]
[explosion]
[melancholy music continues]
[screeching]
[exhales]
The Prime Nergal.
What in the world happened?
What the hell is this?
[Hecate] This can't be real.
[gasps] How did this happen?
[Zirco] Oh.
[screeches]
[low growl]
[people clamoring, screaming]
I have to help!
Wait, Chorogy!
[tense music playing]
[people clamor in alarm]
[man] It's opening! It's open!
[squawks]
[metallic clanging]
[Sapphire grunts]
[screams echo]
[Sapphire straining]
[effort scream]
[screeching]
[Rock grunting]
The timing couldn't be worse.
Don't worry. I think it's just a sprain.
Wait, where's Chorogy?
He ran off up ahead.
[people whimper distantly]
[cracking]
[girl screaming]
Watch out! [grunts]
[thudding]
[Chorogy panting]
[whimpers]
[Chorogy chuckles]
-You're all right now.
-Mm-hmm.
[woman] Oh! Thank you so much.
-Oh!
-Thanks, mister.
I may not be able to fight,
but I can help people.
[distant groaning, howling]
Huh?
[gasps]
You're kidding.
[explosion]
[Nergal shrieks]
[all gasping]
Wait, was that…
[screaming] Chorogy!
[dramatic music playing]
[breathing shakily]
You can do it, Sapphire!
Please, Sapphire! Take out that Nergal!
-Take it down!
We're counting on you, Sapphire!
[dramatic music continues]
[man 1] Someone's fighting it.
[man 2] Is someone trying to stop it?
[woman] Is it the Angel of Hope?
It doesn't matter who it is.
We're begging you. Please, save us!
[dramatic music continues]
[Sapphire grunting, straining]
[grunting]
[man 1] What is that?
[woman] It's the Angel!
Angel of Hope,
please save us.
[sword clanking]
[grunts]
[music intensifies]
[sword clanking]
[effort scream]
[fearful panting]
[music fades]
[low rumbling]
[roaring]
[gasps] Hmm.
[explosion]
[breathing shakily]
[loud splash]
[clinking]
[rain pattering]
It's still here?
I defeated the Nergal.
Why are we still inside the Pillar?
We're still here because
the King of Ash is still alive.
[gasping]
[water bubbling]
[calm music playing]
[electrical buzzing]
[pensive music playing]
[people murmuring]
[Pine's father] We should at least try and
get Pine evacuated to the upper levels.
I'll see if my connection can help.
[Pine's mother]
I pray our child can be spared.
Oh, Lord Mitra!
Please help us.
[Pine] This world…
it's the worst.
But I think I'm the worst part about it.
Sapphire risked her life.
She fought to protect everyone.
What did I do?
Nothing at all.
[Sapphire] Let's try and find something
we can do together.
But if that's the case,
then you're gonna have to be my friend.
[Pine] Sapphire…
I'm supposed to be her friend.
I should've gone with her
when she was taken away.
I should have shared more, asked more.
[Nergal screeches]
I should've called out to her
when she needed support.
[panting]
I just let her go in alone,
even when it seemed hopeless.
I did nothing to help her.
I'm just the one
who always needs protecting.
As a friend, I'm a total failure.
[panting]
[liquid bubbling]
This must be what was amplifying
her inexplicable energy.
Have you prepared the altar?
[Mitra] It will be ready shortly,
Your Holiness.
Excellent.
Gather the children for the ritual,
and any Mitra volunteers
willing to sacrifice their life.
-Yes, sir.
It doesn't have to be this way.
Why are you still going
to sacrifice the orphans?
Why can't we sacrifice Sapphire instead?
She should be our sacrifice.
You still don't understand.
That would only be violence
for violence's sake.
On the contrary, that impulse
would only worsen the situation.
But why?
It is not a curse but a creed,
the Nergal are the repetition
of life and death,
of creation and destruction.
Our emotions and memories
are bound to them.
We are trapped in an endless cycle
of chaos and struggle
where mankind
will never defeat the Nergal.
[tools hammering]
All that we have to soothe us
is our prayers.
Only through heartfelt mourning
can we find calm
in this riotously irrational world.
We offer up our devotion
to the countless souls
and memories residing within the Nergal.
And for that, profound sorrow
and compassion are required.
Carved from the depths of the heart.
The pure souls of the orphans
that our church has so lovingly raised,
they are the fuel
for that compassion and sorrow.
We Mitra have no feelings for that girl,
so she will not serve our purpose.
This is not Silverland.
It is only through pain and suffering
that our prayers are delivered.
Prayer without pain
is purposeless and ineffective.
[breathing shakily]
Now we begin our sacred work.
We will try to mitigate the losses
by minimizing the sacrifices
as much as we possibly can.
The time has come.
He is here.
[ominous music playing]
[panting]
It took you long enough, Pine.
I'm here.
We're all here together.
It's about to start.
All systems are functioning normally.
[rumbling]
[thunderous footsteps]
What's that?
That is the King of Ash.
Begin the holy ritual.
♪ King ♪
♪ O King ♪
♪ Grant me ♪
♪ Your divine guidance ♪
♪ For I am ♪
♪ A blue soul ♪
♪ Your faithful ♪
♪ Angel of prayer ♪
♪ King ♪
♪ O King ♪
♪ Grant me ♪
♪ Pure joy ♪
♪ For I am
A blue destiny ♪
And in the end,
I wasn't able to help anyone.
And even worse, it's my fault.
[Zirco] Unbelievable!
[gasps] Look over there.
-It's Sapphire!
-[all gasp]
[Zirco] It is Sapphire!
[Rock] But why isn't she transforming?
[groans softly]
[gasps] It's gone!
Where's her ribbon?
She can't use her power without it!
[Hecate] Where did it go?
[Tack and Chick exclaiming]
It's almost complete.
All that remains
is to offer up the orphans.
And with this, let our prayers be heard
and the King of Ash be pacified.
We cannot allow their lives to be wasted.
[breathing shakily]
♪ King ♪
♪ O King ♪
♪ Grant me
Your warm embrace ♪
[yelling]
Stop right there!
[singing continues] ♪ For I am ♪
♪ A blue bud ♪
Velvet, wait!
[Mitra guard] Don't let him get away!
[screeching]
What's the commotion?
Your Holiness,
it appears Velvet has escaped.
-Capture him at once.
-Yes, sir.
[effort scream]
-[grunting]
-[swords clashing]
What are those immigrants doing here?
[Mitra guard]
Don't let them get any closer!
Huh?
[exclaims]
[whimpering]
Give that back!
[guard grunts]
[Pope] Stop him! He mustn't get away!
Chick!
-Got it!
-We're counting on you!
[exclaims]
[guards grunting]
[guard] Get over here!
-Hecate!
-Leave it to me!
[all grunting]
[effort scream]
[straining]
Hecate, over here!
-[grunts]
-Whoa!
Pine!
Grab on!
[gasping]
[effort scream]
[straining]
[yelling]
[Rock grunting]
[grunting]
Pine!
Go!
Sapphire!
I know I don't have the power
to save the world,
but I couldn't just
sit back and do nothing.
You're always there to protect me,
but I needed to do something for myself.
[Sapphire] Thanks, Pine.
But maybe this wasn't
the reason why I survived.
The reason why you survived?
The only reason I need
is that you're my best friend.
You're Sapphire.
[gasps]
But I'm so weak.
I don't think I can win.
I'm just…
I'm cursed.
A curse is something that's made of words.
And that means words can break them.
[Sapphire] Huh?
Sapphire, you've been
fighting for so long.
It's just been one big struggle.
[gasps softly]
You've been through so much suffering.
But you've made it this far, haven't you?
How can you say you're weak?
You're the Princess Knight,
and that makes you my hero!
[Sapphire sighs]
[Sapphire breathing shakily]
Thank you, Pine.
I needed that.
[screeching]
[yelling]
[Mitra guard] No, you don't.
Nazuna, Hakobe! Don't worry.
I've got you now.
-Is that you, Velvet?
Is this is really where it all ends?
Someone, please!
[grunting]
The Princess Knight, to the rescue!
-The Princess Knight…
-To the rescue!
Sapphire, how did you…
Don't worry, guys, let me handle this.
Try and get everyone to safety.
Can you really save them?
And I don't just mean the children,
but the people in the country, too.
Watch me.
It's what I'm meant to do with this power.
[gasps softly]
[giggles]
[captivating music playing]
[roaring]
[electrical buzzing]
7 YEARS EARLIER
[calm music playing]
[child giggles]
[both gasp]
[gasps]
[grunting softly]
Where am I?
Wait, I remember you.
Huh? [grunts]
Huh.
Is anyone there?
[echoing]
-[doors thud]
-[Sapphire grunting]
[orchestral music playing]
[gasps]
Is there anyone here?
[man] You've done well.
[Sapphire gasps]
Who are you?
It looks like you don't remember.
Uh…
Don't be afraid.
Here no one can be hurt anymore.
[Sapphire] What do you mean?
It means you carried out your role
and fulfilled your destiny.
[Sapphire] Chorogy?
Is that really you?
Of course.
[gasps]
[Sapphire] Thank goodness!
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry I couldn't save you.
Forgive me! [sobs]
But who's he?
One of the many other heroes
who challenged the Nergal.
So he's just like us, I guess.
You fought them, too?
You fought the Nergal?
I did. But now that painful battle
is at an end.
It's as I said,
in this place,
no one hurts, no one suffers.
A place within history and memory
where all who reside,
live in peace and contentment.
An alternate reality,
something that could have been.
It is an endless story.
Ash is the soul scorched by the flame.
It is death itself,
and in death, each soul is purified.
And in time, is reborn.
This is a place
where those souls can rest.
[gasps]
It's the kind of fate people long for.
[Sapphire] No, this is a dream.
Everyone outside hasn't given up.
So makes what you think I will?
[scoffs]
Someone's been awaiting your arrival.
[rumbling]
BEFORE THE ALTAR
[Pope grunts]
What has that girl done?
It hasn't moved since she toppled it.
Is she all right in there?
Sapphire, you…
[machinery clanking]
Time to put this to use.
INSIDE THE NERGAL
-[gentle music playing]
-[people chattering]
[Sapphire] And then…
Then I took down the Nergal
like it was nothing.
What do you think?
Pretty amazing, right?
[Queen] Yes, darling.
You are quite amazing, Sapphire.
[giggling]
You know…
Mama, since I was a little girl,
all I ever wanted was to hear your praise.
Oh, Sapphire.
[Sapphire] I was a handful.
You were always getting mad at me
for something.
But all I ever wanted to hear
was, "Good job," or, "That's my girl."
You know?
That's all.
Sapphire, you never did anything wrong.
I couldn't bear the thought of losing you.
You meant more than the world to me
and I made you suffer for it.
Don't say that, Mother. It's fine.
Let's start over from the beginning.
I want to apologize.
Darling, I'm sorry.
I thought I was
protecting you in the past.
I was obsessed with your training.
It was arrogance, nothing more.
And it ended up hurting you.
Only now can I say it.
My words must have cut like a sword.
My silence must have
bound you like chains.
[sobs] Never did I imagine
I would experience
such deep regret as a mother.
Oh, Mother!
[chiming]
[Pine and Velvet]
Don't give in! Come back to reality!
♪ Long, long ago ♪
♪ A lone girl ♪
♪ Wandered the land ♪
[Sembry]
Do you think this'll actually work?
It will!
-Don't give up! Sapphire!
-Sapphire, we believe in you!
[gasps]
[Queen] What's the matter, Sapphire?
♪ The poor villagers… ♪
Mother, Father…
[Queen] You still can't forgive me,
can you, my darling?
I suppose I understand.
But I just wanted to see
your beautiful face once more.
[Sapphire] Oh, Mother,
I wanted to see your face, too.
I want to throw this door open.
I want to live with everyone
here in Silverland again.
But this…
This place…
it isn't real.
[crying]
[Queen] Here's a present for you.
[King] It looks wonderful on her!
-[Queen] I love you, Sapphire.
-[King] I love you so much!
[sobs]
♪ You offered the same prayer
Again and again ♪
[Sapphire] I'm thankful you finally
made me realize it.
[sobbing] For the first time ever,
I can say it.
Both Mother and Father are dead.
I'm heartbroken. It hurts.
[sniffling]
[footsteps approaching]
[whooshing]
The factor of the King of Ash.
There it is.
So…
you've chosen the pain of reality
over the peace of memories?
That's right.
[chiming]
'Cause I'm… the Princess Knight.
Attack!
[Sapphire grunting]
[grunting]
[Sapphire straining]
[Velvet] Sapphire! Get down!
Amazing!
Thanks for that!
Get to the Factor.
Leave them to us.
[grunts]
Sapphire!
[effort scream]
[grunting]
Why you…
[Sapphire yelling]
What's happening now?
[grunts]
[Sapphire exclaiming, yelling]
[screaming]
I'm not done yet!
[straining]
[panting]
There's nothing you can do, Sapphire.
[Sapphire grunting]
And it's not just you.
No one in here can stop it.
Well then, I'm glad there are
people outside fighting.
[both grunting]
[Sapphire] I can't fail.
This time, I have to protect everyone,
or I'll never be saved!
-Sorry. [grunts]
-[groans]
But my peace and fulfillment
aren't found here!
You'll never win!
[straining]
[Sapphire grunts]
[Sapphire] Ow, that hurt.
I'll make you pay for that.
Huh? They're gone!
[scoffs]
This has happened countless times before.
And not a single hero
has changed the cycle.
Oh, yeah?
[grunts] Take that, and that, and that,
and that, and that, and that, and that,
and that, and that, and that…
Huh? [screams]
Go on. It's yours.
[Sapphire exclaims]
[yelling]
[clatters]
It's impossible, Sapphire. Forget it.
Get out of the way!
[both] Sapphire!
[Sapphire grunting]
Yoo-hoo!
Catch me now, Donkey!
[both] Do it, Sapphire!
[growling in frustration]
[Sapphire grunts]
[all straining]
[all yelling]
[screaming] You can't change this world!
[Sapphire grunting]
Even if I can't, I'm still gonna try.
All right.
[effort scream]
[screeching]
[all gasping]
[straining]
[bubbling]
[screaming]
[dramatic music]
[applause]
[people cheering]
[gentle music playing]
TAKARAZUKA REVUE
[crowd] Encore! Encore!
Encore! Encore! Encore!
Were you destined to be me somewhere else?
Are you another version of my soul?
Thank you for everything.
I hope the new world that you're going to
is a beautiful and happy one.
[music continues]
PRINCESS KNIGHT
OSAMU TEZUKA
[screeching]
[Sapphire]
May all these souls at last find peace.
[triumphant music playing]
[people exclaiming]
[music continues]
[all gasping]
Sapphire, you did it!
She saved us!
[chuckles softly]
[Sapphire panting]
[Sapphire] Hey, guys!
-Huh?
-[Sapphire] Hey, you guys!
[Pine laughs]
-[Zirco] Sapphire!
-[all] You did it! Sapphire!
[Sapphire laughing]
Why do you all look like
you've seen a ghost?
Did you ever doubt me?
The Princess Knight to the rescue again!
I would have let the world burn
if it meant I'd be saving these children.
And I imagine that's how
your parents felt, too.
You might be right.
What will the Princess Knight do now?
I'd be happy to help
in any way that I can.
Thanks, but first, I'm going
to pay a visit to Silver Land.
I have to pay my respects.
Mourn Mother, Father and the kingdom.
You can bet I'm coming, too!
[Sapphire chuckles]
[all] What?!
Come on!
Don't make this any harder.
So you're really leaving us?
I've made up my mind.
But once I get there,
I'll write to you, Pine.
If you and the others
hadn't been there cheering me on,
I never would have won.
Because Pine, you were
the one who broke my curse.
[giggles]
Sapphire!
[Sapphire grunts, chuckles]
I'll visit.
I'll come and see you in Silver Land.
'Cause, we're friends.
Friends forever, right?
Yeah, we're all friends forever.
[triumphant music playing]
[Sapphire] Not a single Nergal
appeared again since then.
It seemed like at long last,
the cycle had been broken.
I hope someday,
or better yet, starting now,
I hope that the people
who have been hurt can begin to heal,
however slowly.
And that their newfound future
is brilliantly bright.
[closing theme music playing]
["The Winter-Worn Traveler" playing]